[
  {
  "chapter":1,
  "chapterName":"Rotational Motion",
  "chapterPhoto": "@drawable/p1",
  "content":[{
    "sentenceId": 1,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "In a circular motion, the object just moves in a circle.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 1,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In a circular motion, the object just moves in a circle.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 2,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In a ______ motion, the object just moves in a circle.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 3,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In a ______ motion, the object just moves in a circle.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": [
          "circular",
          "tangential",
          "angular"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 4,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In a circular motion, the object just moves in a ______.",
        "answer": "circle",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 5,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In a circular motion, the object just moves in a ______.",
        "answer": "circle",
        "options": [
          "circle",
          "parallel",
          "dimension"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 2,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Example of circular motion is artificial satellites going around the earth at a constant height.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 6,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Example of tangential motion is artificial satellites going around the earth at a constant height.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 7,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Example of ______ motion is artificial satellites going around the earth at a constant height.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 8,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Example of ______ motion is artificial satellites going around the earth at a constant height.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": [
          "circular",
          "angular",
          "tangential"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 3,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "In rotational motion, the object rotates about an axis.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 9,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In rotational motion, the object rotates about an axis.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 10,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In ______ motion, the object rotates about an axis.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 11,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In ______ motion, the object rotates about an axis.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": [
          "rotational",
          "circular",
          "linear"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 12,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In rotational motion, the object rotates about an ______.",
        "answer": "axis",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 13,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In rotational motion, the object rotates about an ______.",
        "answer": "axis",
        "options": [
          "axis",
          "orbit",
          "center"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 4,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The rotation of the earth about its own axis which creates the circle of day and night is the rotational motion.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 14,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The rotation of the earth about its own axis which creates the circle of day and night is the rotational motion.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 15,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The rotation of the earth about its own axis which creates the circle of day and night is the ______ motion.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 16,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The rotation of the earth about its own axis which creates the circle of day and night is the ______ motion.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": [
          "rotational",
          "revolutionary",
          "orbital"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 5,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Motion of the blades of a fan is the rotational motion.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 17,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Motion of the blades of a fan is the circular motion.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 18,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Motion of the blades of a fan is the ______ motion.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 19,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Motion of the blades of a fan is the ______ motion.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": [
          "rotational",
          "circular",
          "linear"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 6,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Motion of a Ferris wheel in an amusement park is the rotational motion.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 20,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Motion of a Ferris wheel in an amusement park is the rotational motion.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 21,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Motion of a Ferris wheel in an amusement park is the ______ motion.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 22,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Motion of a Ferris wheel in an amusement park is the ______ motion.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": [
          "rotational",
          "circular",
          "translational"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 7,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "A rigid body is a body that does not deform or change shape by deforming force.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 23,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "A rigid body is a body that does not deform or change shape by deforming force.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 24,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "A ______ is a body that does not deform or change shape by deforming force.",
        "answer": "rigid body",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 25,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "A ______ is a body that does not deform or change shape by deforming force.",
        "answer": "rigid body",
        "options": [
          "rigid body",
          "elastic body",
          "plastic body"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 26,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "A rigid body is a body that does ______ deform or change shape by deforming force.",
        "answer": "not",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 27,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "A rigid body is a body that does ______ deform or change shape by deforming force.",
        "answer": "not",
        "options": [
          "not",
          "always",
          "easily"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 8,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "No matter how a rigid body moves, the distance between any two particles within the body remains constant.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 28,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "No matter how a rigid body moves, the distance between any two particles within the body is always changing.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 29,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "No matter how a rigid body moves, the distance between any two particles within the body remains ______.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 30,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "No matter how a rigid body moves, the distance between any two particles within the body remains ______.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": [
          "constant",
          "variable",
          "zero"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 9,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "If a rigid body is in rotational motion, all the particles constituting it undergo circular motion about a common axis.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 31,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "If a rigid body is in rotational motion, all the particles constituting it undergo circular motion about a common axis.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 32,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If a rigid body is in ______ motion, all the particles constituting it undergo circular motion about a common axis.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 33,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If a rigid body is in ______ motion, all the particles constituting it undergo circular motion about a common axis.",
        "answer": "rotational",
        "options": [
          "rotational",
          "linear",
          "random"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 34,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If a rigid body is in rotational motion, all the particles constituting it undergo ______ motion about a common axis.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 35,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If a rigid body is in rotational motion, all the particles constituting it undergo ______ motion about a common axis.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": [
          "circular",
          "spiral",
          "elliptical"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 10,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "When an object, or a rigid body, rotates, it can speed up or slow down.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 36,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When an object, or a rigid body, rotates, it can speed up or slow down.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 37,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When an object, or a rigid body, rotates, it ______ speed up or slow down.",
        "answer": "can",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 38,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When an object, or a rigid body, rotates, it ______ speed up or slow down.",
        "answer": "can",
        "options": [
          "can",
          "cannot",
          "must"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 11,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "While the speed is changing, the angular velocity is also changing, and the rotating body has an angular acceleration.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 39,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "While the speed is changing, the angular velocity is also changing, and the rotating body has an angular acceleration.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 40,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "While the speed is changing, the angular ______ is also changing, and the rotating body has an angular acceleration.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 41,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "While the speed is changing, the angular ______ is also changing, and the rotating body has an angular acceleration.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": [
          "velocity",
          "displacement",
          "momentum"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 42,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "While the speed is changing, the angular velocity is also changing, and the rotating body has an ______ acceleration.",
        "answer": "angular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 43,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "While the speed is changing, the angular velocity is also changing, and the rotating body has an ______ acceleration.",
        "answer": "angular",
        "options": [
          "angular",
          "linear",
          "centripetal"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 44,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "While the speed is changing, the angular velocity is also changing, and the rotating body has an angular ______.",
        "answer": "acceleration",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 45,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "While the speed is changing, the angular velocity is also changing, and the rotating body has an angular ______.",
        "answer": "acceleration",
        "options": [
          "acceleration",
          "inertia",
          "speed"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 12,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "If the angular velocity changes at a constant rate, then we can say the angular acceleration is constant, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 46,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "If the angular velocity changes at a constant rate, then we can say the angular acceleration is constant, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 47,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the angular ______ changes at a constant rate, then we can say the angular acceleration is constant, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 48,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the angular ______ changes at a constant rate, then we can say the angular acceleration is constant, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": [
          "velocity",
          "acceleration",
          "displacement"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 49,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the angular velocity changes at a ______ rate, then we can say the angular acceleration is constant, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 50,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the angular velocity changes at a ______ rate, then we can say the angular acceleration is constant, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": [
          "constant",
          "variable",
          "increasing"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 51,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the angular velocity changes at a constant rate, then we can say the ______ is constant, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": "angular acceleration",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 52,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the angular velocity changes at a constant rate, then we can say the ______ is constant, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": "angular acceleration",
        "options": [
          "angular acceleration",
          "angular velocity",
          "torque"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 53,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the angular velocity changes at a constant rate, then we can say the angular acceleration is ______, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 54,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the angular velocity changes at a constant rate, then we can say the angular acceleration is ______, and the motion is called the rotational motion under constant acceleration.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": [
          "constant",
          "zero",
          "variable"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 13,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "For an object that rotates with a constant angular acceleration, the kinematic equations for rotational motion can be derived in terms of the angular displacement, angular velocity and angular acceleration of the object at any instant of time.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 55,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "For an object that rotates with a constant angular acceleration, the kinematic equations for rotational motion can be derived in terms of the angular displacement, angular velocity and angular acceleration of the object at any instant of time.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 56,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "For an object that rotates with a constant angular acceleration, the ______ equations for rotational motion can be derived in terms of the angular displacement, angular velocity and angular acceleration of the object at any instant of time.",
        "answer": "kinematic",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 57,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "For an object that rotates with a constant angular acceleration, the ______ equations for rotational motion can be derived in terms of the angular displacement, angular velocity and angular acceleration of the object at any instant of time.",
        "answer": "kinematic",
        "options": [
          "kinematic",
          "dynamic",
          "static"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 14,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "All particles of the body move in a circle lying on a plane that is perpendicular to the axis, such that the centre of rotation lies on the axis.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 58,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "All particles of the body move in a circle lying on a plane that is parallel to the axis, such that the centre of rotation lies on the axis.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 59,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "All particles of the body move in a circle lying on a plane that is ______ to the axis, such that the centre of rotation lies on the axis.",
        "answer": "perpendicular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 60,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "All particles of the body move in a circle lying on a plane that is ______ to the axis, such that the centre of rotation lies on the axis.",
        "answer": "perpendicular",
        "options": [
          "perpendicular",
          "parallel",
          "tangential"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 15,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "All particles of an object rotating around the axis of rotation move in a circular path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 61,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "All particles of an object rotating around the axis of rotation move in a circular path.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 62,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "All particles of an object rotating around the axis of rotation move in a ______ path.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 63,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "All particles of an object rotating around the axis of rotation move in a ______ path.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": [
          "circular",
          "linear",
          "elliptical"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 16,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "Since the direction of linear velocity is tangent to the path, the linear velocity is also called tangential velocity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 64,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Since the direction of linear velocity is tangent to the path, the linear velocity is also called tangential velocity.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 17,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "If the magnitude of the angular velocity of a rotating object changes, the magnitude of the linear velocity will also change, and the object will have a tangential acceleration.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 65,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "If the magnitude of the angular velocity of a rotating object changes, the magnitude of the linear velocity will also change, and the object will have a tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 66,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the magnitude of the angular ______ of a rotating object changes, the magnitude of the linear velocity will also change, and the object will have a tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 67,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the magnitude of the angular ______ of a rotating object changes, the magnitude of the linear velocity will also change, and the object will have a tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": [
          "velocity",
          "acceleration",
          "force"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 68,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the magnitude of the angular velocity of a rotating object changes, the magnitude of the ______ will also change, and the object will have a tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": "linear velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 69,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the magnitude of the angular velocity of a rotating object changes, the magnitude of the ______ will also change, and the object will have a tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": "linear velocity",
        "options": [
          "linear velocity",
          "angular velocity",
          "radial velocity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 70,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the magnitude of the angular velocity of a rotating object changes, the magnitude of the linear velocity will also change, and the object will have a ______.",
        "answer": "tangential acceleration",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 71,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the magnitude of the angular velocity of a rotating object changes, the magnitude of the linear velocity will also change, and the object will have a ______.",
        "answer": "tangential acceleration",
        "options": [
          "tangential acceleration",
          "centripetal acceleration",
          "radial acceleration"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 18,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The direction of the tangential acceleration is always tangent to the circular path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 72,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The direction of the tangential acceleration is always tangent to the circular path.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 73,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The direction of the tangential acceleration is always ______ to the circular path.",
        "answer": "tangent",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 74,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The direction of the tangential acceleration is always ______ to the circular path.",
        "answer": "tangent",
        "options": [
          "tangent",
          "perpendicular",
          "radial"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 75,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The direction of the tangential acceleration is always tangent to the ______ path.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 76,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The direction of the tangential acceleration is always tangent to the ______ path.",
        "answer": "circular",
        "options": [
          "circular",
          "straight",
          "elliptical"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 19,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The tangential acceleration of a rotating object is a measure of how fast the tangential velocity changes.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 77,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The tangential acceleration of a rotating object is a measure of how fast the tangential velocity changes.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 78,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The tangential acceleration of a rotating object is a measure of how fast the ______ velocity changes.",
        "answer": "tangential",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 79,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The tangential acceleration of a rotating object is a measure of how fast the ______ velocity changes.",
        "answer": "tangential",
        "options": [
          "tangential",
          "angular",
          "centripetal"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 80,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The tangential acceleration of a rotating object is a measure of how fast the tangential ______ changes.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 81,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The tangential acceleration of a rotating object is a measure of how fast the tangential ______ changes.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": [
          "velocity",
          "acceleration",
          "displacement"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 20,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The direction of the angular velocity vector is perpendicular to the plane of rotation, and along the axis of rotation.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 82,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The direction of the angular velocity vector is parallel to the plane of rotation, and along the axis of rotation.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 83,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The direction of the ______ vector is perpendicular to the plane of rotation, and along the axis of rotation.",
        "answer": "angular velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 84,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The direction of the ______ vector is perpendicular to the plane of rotation, and along the axis of rotation.",
        "answer": "angular velocity",
        "options": [
          "angular velocity",
          "linear velocity",
          "torque"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 85,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The direction of the angular velocity vector is ______ to the plane of rotation, and along the axis of rotation.",
        "answer": "perpendicular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 86,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The direction of the angular velocity vector is ______ to the plane of rotation, and along the axis of rotation.",
        "answer": "perpendicular",
        "options": [
          "perpendicular",
          "parallel",
          "tangent"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 21,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The direction of the angular velocity vector is usually specified by the right-hand rule.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 87,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The direction of the angular velocity vector is usually specified by the right-hand rule.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 88,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The direction of the ______ vector is usually specified by the right-hand rule.",
        "answer": "angular velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 89,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The direction of the ______ vector is usually specified by the right-hand rule.",
        "answer": "angular velocity",
        "options": [
          "angular velocity",
          "torque",
          "centripetal force"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 90,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The direction of the angular velocity vector is usually specified by the ______ rule.",
        "answer": "right-hand",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 91,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The direction of the angular velocity vector is usually specified by the ______ rule.",
        "answer": "right-hand",
        "options": [
          "right-hand",
          "left-hand",
          "corkscrew"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 22,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "When we wrap the right hand around the axis of rotation, the fingers are pointing in the direction of rotation.In this case, the thumb points in the direction of the angular velocity vector.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 92,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When we wrap the right hand around the axis of rotation, the fingers are pointing in the direction of rotation.In this case, the thumb points in the direction of the angular velocity vector.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 93,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When we wrap the right hand around the axis of rotation, the fingers are pointing in the direction of rotation.In this case, the ______ points in the direction of the angular velocity vector.",
        "answer": "thumb",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 94,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When we wrap the right hand around the axis of rotation, the fingers are pointing in the direction of rotation.In this case, the ______ points in the direction of the angular velocity vector.",
        "answer": "thumb",
        "options": [
          "thumb",
          "fingers",
          "palm"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 23,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "When the angular velocity is increasing, the angular acceleration vector points in the same direction as the angular velocity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 95,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is decreasing, the angular acceleration vector points in the same direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 96,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is ______, the angular acceleration vector points in the same direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": "increasing",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 97,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is ______, the angular acceleration vector points in the same direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": "increasing",
        "options": [
          "increasing",
          "decreasing",
          "constant"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 98,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is increasing, the angular acceleration vector points in the ______ direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": "same",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 99,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is increasing, the angular acceleration vector points in the ______ direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": "same",
        "options": [
          "same",
          "opposite",
          "perpendicular"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 24,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "When the angular velocity is decreasing, the angular acceleration vector points in the opposite direction as the angular velocity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 100,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is decreasing, the angular acceleration vector points in the opposite direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 101,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is ______, the angular acceleration vector points in the opposite direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": "decreasing",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 102,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is ______, the angular acceleration vector points in the opposite direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": "decreasing",
        "options": [
          "decreasing",
          "increasing",
          "constant"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 103,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is decreasing, the angular acceleration vector points in the ______ direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": "opposite",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 104,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When the angular velocity is decreasing, the angular acceleration vector points in the ______ direction as the angular velocity.",
        "answer": "opposite",
        "options": [
          "opposite",
          "same",
          "perpendicular"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 25,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "The change in direction of the velocity constitutes an acceleration.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 105,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The change in direction of the velocity constitutes an acceleration.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 106,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The change in direction of the velocity constitutes an ______.",
        "answer": "acceleration",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 107,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The change in direction of the velocity constitutes an ______.",
        "answer": "acceleration",
        "options": [
          "acceleration",
          "velocity",
          "force"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 26,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "An object revolving in a circle is continuously accelerating, even when the speed remains constant.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 108,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "An object revolving in a circle is continuously accelerating, even when the speed remains constant.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 109,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An object revolving in a circle is continuously ______, even when the speed remains constant.",
        "answer": "accelerating",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 110,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An object revolving in a circle is continuously ______, even when the speed remains constant.",
        "answer": "accelerating",
        "options": [
          "accelerating",
          "decelerating",
          "at constant velocity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 111,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An object revolving in a circle is continuously accelerating, even when the ______ remains constant.",
        "answer": "speed",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 112,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An object revolving in a circle is continuously accelerating, even when the ______ remains constant.",
        "answer": "speed",
        "options": [
          "speed",
          "velocity",
          "acceleration"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 27,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "For uniform circular motion, the centripetal acceleration vector points towards the centre of the circular path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 113,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion, the centripetal acceleration vector points towards the centre of the circular path.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 114,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion, the ______ vector points towards the centre of the circular path.",
        "answer": "centripetal acceleration",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 115,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion, the ______ vector points towards the centre of the circular path.",
        "answer": "centripetal acceleration",
        "options": [
          "centripetal acceleration",
          "tangential acceleration",
          "linear velocity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 116,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion, the centripetal acceleration vector points towards the ______ of the circular path.",
        "answer": "centre",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 117,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion, the centripetal acceleration vector points towards the ______ of the circular path.",
        "answer": "centre",
        "options": [
          "centre",
          "edge",
          "tangent"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 28,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "For uniform circular motion,the linear velocity vector is tangential to the circular path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 118,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "For non-uniform circular motion,the linear velocity vector is tangential to the circular path.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 119,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion,the ______ vector is tangential to the circular path.",
        "answer": "linear velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 120,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion,the ______ vector is tangential to the circular path.",
        "answer": "linear velocity",
        "options": [
          "linear velocity",
          "angular velocity",
          "centripetal acceleration"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 121,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion,the linear velocity vector is ______ to the circular path.",
        "answer": "tangential",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 122,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion,the linear velocity vector is ______ to the circular path.",
        "answer": "tangential",
        "options": [
          "tangential",
          "radial",
          "normal"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 29,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "The centripetal acceleration and the linear velocity are perpendicular to each other at every point in the path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 123,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The centripetal acceleration and the linear velocity are perpendicular to each other at every point in the path.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 124,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The centripetal acceleration and the linear velocity are ______ to each other at every point in the path.",
        "answer": "perpendicular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 125,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The centripetal acceleration and the linear velocity are ______ to each other at every point in the path.",
        "answer": "perpendicular",
        "options": [
          "perpendicular",
          "parallel",
          "collinear"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 126,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The centripetal acceleration and the linear velocity are perpendicular to each other at ______ point in the path.",
        "answer": "every",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 127,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The centripetal acceleration and the linear velocity are perpendicular to each other at ______ point in the path.",
        "answer": "every",
        "options": [
          "every",
          "some",
          "one specific"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 30,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "In non-uniform circular motion, there is tangential acceleration in addition to the centripetal acceleration.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 128,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In non-uniform circular motion, there is tangential acceleration in addition to the centripetal acceleration.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 129,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In ______ circular motion, there is tangential acceleration in addition to the centripetal acceleration.",
        "answer": "non-uniform",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 130,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In ______ circular motion, there is tangential acceleration in addition to the centripetal acceleration.",
        "answer": "non-uniform",
        "options": [
          "non-uniform",
          "uniform",
          "linear"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 131,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In non-uniform circular motion, there is ______ in addition to the centripetal acceleration.",
        "answer": "tangential acceleration",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 132,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In non-uniform circular motion, there is ______ in addition to the centripetal acceleration.",
        "answer": "tangential acceleration",
        "options": [
          "tangential acceleration",
          "constant velocity",
          "radial velocity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 31,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "An object in non-uniform circular motion has a resultant acceleration that is the vector sum of the centripetal acceleration and the tangential acceleration.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 133,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "An object in non-uniform circular motion has a resultant acceleration that is the vector sum of the centripetal acceleration and the tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 134,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An object in ______ circular motion has a resultant acceleration that is the vector sum of the centripetal acceleration and the tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": "non-uniform",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 135,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An object in ______ circular motion has a resultant acceleration that is the vector sum of the centripetal acceleration and the tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": "non-uniform",
        "options": [
          "non-uniform",
          "uniform",
          "rectilinear"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 136,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An object in non-uniform circular motion has a resultant acceleration that is the ______ of the centripetal acceleration and the tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": "vector sum",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 137,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An object in non-uniform circular motion has a resultant acceleration that is the ______ of the centripetal acceleration and the tangential acceleration.",
        "answer": "vector sum",
        "options": [
          "vector sum",
          "scalar sum",
          "vector product"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 32,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "Centripetal acceleration is present in both uniform and non-uniform circular motion.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 138,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Tangential acceleration is present in both uniform and non-uniform circular motion.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 139,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is present in both uniform and non-uniform circular motion.",
        "answer": "Centripetal acceleration",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 140,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is present in both uniform and non-uniform circular motion.",
        "answer": "Centripetal acceleration",
        "options": [
          "Centripetal acceleration",
          "Tangential acceleration",
          "Constant velocity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 33,
    "chapter": "chapter 1",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "Tangential acceleration is present in  non-uniform circular motion",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 141,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Tangential acceleration is present in  non-uniform circular motion",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 142,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is present in  non-uniform circular motion",
        "answer": "Tangential acceleration",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 143,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is present in  non-uniform circular motion",
        "answer": "Tangential acceleration",
        "options": [
          "Tangential acceleration",
          "Centripetal acceleration",
          "Uniform velocity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 144,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Tangential acceleration is present in  ______ circular motion",
        "answer": "non-uniform",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 145,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Tangential acceleration is present in  ______ circular motion",
        "answer": "non-uniform",
        "options": [
          "non-uniform",
          "uniform",
          "linear"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  }
]
  },
  {
    "chapter":2,
    "chapterName":"Forces In Circular Motion",
    "chapterPhoto":"@drawable/p2",

    "content":[
  {
    "sentenceId": 1,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "According to Newton’s second law, an object that is accelerating must have a net force acting on it.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 1,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "According to Newton’s second law, an object that is accelerating must have a net force acting on it.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 2,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "According to ______, an object that is accelerating must have a net force acting on it.",
        "answer": "Newton’s second law",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 3,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "According to ______, an object that is accelerating must have a net force acting on it.",
        "answer": "Newton’s second law",
        "options": [
          "Newton’s second law",
          "Newton's first law",
          "Newton's third law"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 2,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "An object moving in a circle, such as a ball on the end of a string, must have a force applied to it to keep it moving in the circle.This force is known as the centripetal force.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 4,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "An object moving in a circle, such as a ball on the end of a string, must have a force applied to it to keep it moving in the circle.This force is known as the centripetal force.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 5,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An object moving in a circle, such as a ball on the end of a string, must have a force applied to it to keep it moving in the circle.This force is known as the ______ force.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 6,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An object moving in a circle, such as a ball on the end of a string, must have a force applied to it to keep it moving in the circle.This force is known as the ______ force.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": [
          "centripetal",
          "centrifugal",
          "frictional"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 3,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "For uniform circular motion (speed v = constant), the acceleration is centripetal acceleration which is directed towards the centre of the circle at any moment.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 7,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion (speed v = constant), the acceleration is centripetal acceleration which is directed towards the centre of the circle at any moment.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 8,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion (speed v = constant), the acceleration is ______ acceleration which is directed towards the centre of the circle at any moment.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 9,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "For uniform circular motion (speed v = constant), the acceleration is ______ acceleration which is directed towards the centre of the circle at any moment.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": [
          "centripetal",
          "tangential",
          "linear"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 4,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "According to Newton’s second law, an object in a circular motion requires a net force directed towards the centre of the circle. This net force is called the centripetal force.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 10,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "According to Newton’s first law, an object in a circular motion requires a net force directed towards the centre of the circle. This net force is called the centripetal force.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 11,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "According to Newton’s second law, an object in a circular motion requires a net force directed towards the centre of the circle. This net force is called the ______.",
        "answer": "centripetal force",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 12,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "According to Newton’s second law, an object in a circular motion requires a net force directed towards the centre of the circle. This net force is called the ______.",
        "answer": "centripetal force",
        "options": [
          "centripetal force",
          "centrifugal force",
          "net acceleration"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 5,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The tension in the string provides the required centripetal force for the ball to keep moving in circular path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 13,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The tension in the string provides the required centripetal force for the ball to keep moving in circular path.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 14,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The ______ in the string provides the required centripetal force for the ball to keep moving in circular path.",
        "answer": "tension",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 15,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The ______ in the string provides the required centripetal force for the ball to keep moving in circular path.",
        "answer": "tension",
        "options": [
          "tension",
          "gravity",
          "friction"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 6,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "There are different forms of forces which can provide centripetal force depending on the motion of the bodies under various conditions.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 16,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "There are different forms of forces which can provide centripetal force depending on the motion of the bodies under various conditions.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 17,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "There are different forms of forces which can provide centripetal force depending on the ______ of the bodies under various conditions.",
        "answer": "motion",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 18,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "There are different forms of forces which can provide centripetal force depending on the ______ of the bodies under various conditions.",
        "answer": "motion",
        "options": [
          "motion",
          "mass",
          "shape"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 7,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "If the tension force is normal to the direction of the motion of a body moving at constant speed, this force causes the body to move in a circular path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 19,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "If the tension force is normal to the direction of the motion of a body moving at constant speed, this force causes the body to move in a circular path.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 20,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the tension force is ______ to the direction of the motion of a body moving at constant speed, this force causes the body to move in a circular path.",
        "answer": "normal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 21,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the tension force is ______ to the direction of the motion of a body moving at constant speed, this force causes the body to move in a circular path.",
        "answer": "normal",
        "options": [
          "normal",
          "parallel",
          "tangential"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 8,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "An attractive force exists between the sun and the earth in a direction perpendicular to the path of the earth.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 22,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "An attractive force exists between the sun and the earth in a direction parallel to the path of the earth.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 23,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An ______ force exists between the sun and the earth in a direction perpendicular to the path of the earth.",
        "answer": "attractive",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 24,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An ______ force exists between the sun and the earth in a direction perpendicular to the path of the earth.",
        "answer": "attractive",
        "options": [
          "attractive",
          "repulsive",
          "frictional"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 25,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An attractive force exists between the sun and the earth in a direction ______ to the path of the earth.",
        "answer": "perpendicular",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 26,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An attractive force exists between the sun and the earth in a direction ______ to the path of the earth.",
        "answer": "perpendicular",
        "options": [
          "perpendicular",
          "parallel",
          "tangential"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 9,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The gravitational force causes the earth to move a circular path around the sun.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 27,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The gravitational force causes the earth to move a circular path around the sun.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 28,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The ______ force causes the earth to move a circular path around the sun.",
        "answer": "gravitational",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 29,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The ______ force causes the earth to move a circular path around the sun.",
        "answer": "gravitational",
        "options": [
          "gravitational",
          "magnetic",
          "electrostatic"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 10,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "(In an atom), the Coulomb attractive force between the nucleus and the electron acts as the required centripetal force for the electron to move around the nucleus.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 30,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "(In an atom), the Coulomb attractive force between the nucleus and the electron acts as the required centripetal force for the electron to move around the nucleus.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 31,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "(In an atom), the Coulomb attractive force between the nucleus and the electron acts as the required ______ force for the electron to move around the nucleus.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 32,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "(In an atom), the Coulomb attractive force between the nucleus and the electron acts as the required ______ force for the electron to move around the nucleus.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": [
          "centripetal",
          "gravitational",
          "nuclear strong"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 11,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "When a car turns in a circular path or a curve, a frictional force exists between the road and the car tires.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 33,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When a car turns in a circular path or a curve, there's no force exit between the road and the car tires.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 34,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When a car turns in a circular path or a curve, a ______ force exists between the road and the car tires.",
        "answer": "frictional",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 35,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When a car turns in a circular path or a curve, a ______ force exists between the road and the car tires.",
        "answer": "frictional",
        "options": [
          "frictional",
          "gravitational",
          "normal"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 12,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The frictional force acts normally to the direction of the motion of the car, causing the car to move in a curved path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 36,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The frictional force acts normally to the direction of the motion of the car, causing the car to move in a straight path.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 37,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The ______ force acts normally to the direction of the motion of the car, causing the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": "frictional",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 38,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The ______ force acts normally to the direction of the motion of the car, causing the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": "frictional",
        "options": [
          "frictional",
          "normal",
          "gravitational"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 39,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The frictional force acts ______ to the direction of the motion of the car, causing the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": "normally",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 40,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The frictional force acts ______ to the direction of the motion of the car, causing the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": "normally",
        "options": [
          "normally",
          "parallel",
          "tangentially"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 13,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the horizontal, the reaction force of the road acts normally to the car.Resolving the reaction force (normal force) into two components, the horizontal component acts towards the centre of the circle, and helps the car to move in a curved path.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 41,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the horizontal, the reaction force of the road acts normally to the car.Resolving the reaction force (normal force) into two components, the horizontal component acts towards the centre of the circle, and helps the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 42,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the ______, the reaction force of the road acts normally to the car.Resolving the reaction force (normal force) into two components, the horizontal component acts towards the centre of the circle, and helps the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": "horizontal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 43,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the ______, the reaction force of the road acts normally to the car.Resolving the reaction force (normal force) into two components, the horizontal component acts towards the centre of the circle, and helps the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": "horizontal",
        "options": [
          "horizontal",
          "vertical",
          "surface"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 44,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the horizontal, the reaction force of the road acts normally to the car.Resolving the reaction force (normal force) into two components, the ______ component acts towards the centre of the circle, and helps the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": "horizontal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 45,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the horizontal, the reaction force of the road acts normally to the car.Resolving the reaction force (normal force) into two components, the ______ component acts towards the centre of the circle, and helps the car to move in a curved path.",
        "answer": "horizontal",
        "options": [
          "horizontal",
          "vertical",
          "resultant"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 14,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the horizontal, the reaction force of the road acts normally to the car.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 46,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the horizontal, the reaction force of the road acts normally to the car.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 47,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the horizontal, the reaction force of the road acts ______ to the car.",
        "answer": "normally",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 48,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When a car moves in a circular path which is inclined to the horizontal, the reaction force of the road acts ______ to the car.",
        "answer": "normally",
        "options": [
          "normally",
          "parallel",
          "downwards"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 15,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The upward thrust (the lifting force) acts normally to an aeroplane body.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 49,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The upward thrust (the lifting force) acts regularly to an aeroplane body.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 50,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The upward thrust (the lifting force) acts ______ to an aeroplane body.",
        "answer": "normally",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 51,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The upward thrust (the lifting force) acts ______ to an aeroplane body.",
        "answer": "normally",
        "options": [
          "normally",
          "longitudinally",
          "obliquely"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 16,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "When the aeroplane tilts, the horizontal component acts normally to the motion of the aerophane, causing the aero plane to turn in a curve.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 52,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When the aeroplane tilts, the horizontal component acts normally to the motion of the aerophane, causing the aero plane to turn in a curve.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 53,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When the aeroplane tilts, the ______ component acts normally to the motion of the aerophane, causing the aero plane to turn in a curve.",
        "answer": "horizontal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 54,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When the aeroplane tilts, the ______ component acts normally to the motion of the aerophane, causing the aero plane to turn in a curve.",
        "answer": "horizontal",
        "options": [
          "horizontal",
          "vertical",
          "thrust"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 17,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "This means that the horizontal component of the lifting force on the aeroplane provides the centripetal force.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 55,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "This means that the horizontal component of the lifting force on the aeroplane provides the centripetal force.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 56,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "This means that the horizontal component of the lifting force on the aeroplane provides the ______ force.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 57,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "This means that the horizontal component of the lifting force on the aeroplane provides the ______ force.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": [
          "centripetal",
          "lift",
          "thrust"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 18,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "When the aeroplane tilts, the horizontal component acts normally to the motion of the aerophane, causing the aero plane to turn in a curve.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 58,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When the aeroplane tilts, the horizontal component acts normally to the motion of the aerophane, causing the aero plane to turn in a curve.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 19,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "On a flat road (unbanked road), the centripetal force is supplied by friction between the tires and the road.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 59,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "On a flat road (unbanked road), the centripetal force is supplied by friction between the tires and the road.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 60,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "On a flat road (unbanked road), the centripetal force is supplied by ______ between the tires and the road.",
        "answer": "friction",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 61,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "On a flat road (unbanked road), the centripetal force is supplied by ______ between the tires and the road.",
        "answer": "friction",
        "options": [
          "friction",
          "gravity",
          "normal force"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 20,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "If the frictional force is not sufficient, such as under wet and slippery conditions, the car will skid out of the circular path.To prevent this, the road must be banked to provide the necessary centripetal force to the automobiles so that they make a safe turn without skidding.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 62,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "If the frictional force is not sufficient, such as under wet and slippery conditions, the car will skid out of the circular path.To prevent this, the road must be banked to provide the necessary centripetal force to the automobiles so that they make a safe turn without skidding.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 63,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "If the frictional force is not sufficient, such as under wet and slippery conditions, the car will skid out of the circular path.To prevent this, the road must be ______ to provide the necessary centripetal force to the automobiles so that they make a safe turn without skidding.",
        "answer": "banked",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 64,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "If the frictional force is not sufficient, such as under wet and slippery conditions, the car will skid out of the circular path.To prevent this, the road must be ______ to provide the necessary centripetal force to the automobiles so that they make a safe turn without skidding.",
        "answer": "banked",
        "options": [
          "banked",
          "flattened",
          "widened"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 21,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Banking of roads is raising the outer edge of the curved road higher than the inner edge.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 65,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Banking of roads is raising the inner edge of the curved road higher than the inner edge.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 66,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Banking of roads is raising the outer edge of the curved road ______ than the inner edge.",
        "answer": "higher",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 67,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Banking of roads is raising the outer edge of the curved road ______ than the inner edge.",
        "answer": "higher",
        "options": [
          "higher",
          "lower",
          "equal to"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 22,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Centripetal force is the force acting towards the centre of the circular path around which the object is moving whereas the centrifugal force appears to act in a direction pointing away from the centre.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 68,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Centripetal force is the force acting towards the centre of the circular path around which the object is moving whereas the centrifugal force appears to act in a direction pointing away from the centre.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 69,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ force is the force acting towards the centre of the circular path around which the object is moving whereas the centrifugal force appears to act in a direction pointing away from the centre.",
        "answer": "Centripetal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 70,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ force is the force acting towards the centre of the circular path around which the object is moving whereas the centrifugal force appears to act in a direction pointing away from the centre.",
        "answer": "Centripetal",
        "options": [
          "Centripetal",
          "Centrifugal",
          "Frictional"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 71,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Centripetal force is the force acting towards the centre of the circular path around which the object is moving whereas the ______ force appears to act in a direction pointing away from the centre.",
        "answer": "centrifugal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 72,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Centripetal force is the force acting towards the centre of the circular path around which the object is moving whereas the ______ force appears to act in a direction pointing away from the centre.",
        "answer": "centrifugal",
        "options": [
          "centrifugal",
          "centripetal",
          "gravitational"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 23,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "Except centripetal force, there is no other force acting on the ball along the string.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 73,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Except centripetal force, there is no other force acting on the ball along the string.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 74,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Except ______ force, there is no other force acting on the ball along the string.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 75,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Except ______ force, there is no other force acting on the ball along the string.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": [
          "centripetal",
          "gravitational",
          "air resistance"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 24,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "When the car is moving with constant velocity along a straight road, there is no net force on the person.  Hence, the person feels no force acting on him.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 76,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Even the car is moving with constant velocity along a straight road, there is the net force on the person.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 77,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When the car is moving with ______ velocity along a straight road, there is no net force on the person.  Hence, the person feels no force acting on him.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 78,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When the car is moving with ______ velocity along a straight road, there is no net force on the person.  Hence, the person feels no force acting on him.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": [
          "constant",
          "increasing",
          "variable"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 79,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When the car is moving with constant ______ along a straight road, there is no net force on the person.  Hence, the person feels no force acting on him.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 80,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When the car is moving with constant ______ along a straight road, there is no net force on the person.  Hence, the person feels no force acting on him.",
        "answer": "velocity",
        "options": [
          "velocity",
          "speed",
          "acceleration"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 81,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When the car is moving with constant velocity along a ______ road, there is no net force on the person.  Hence, the person feels no force acting on him.",
        "answer": "straight",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 82,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When the car is moving with constant velocity along a ______ road, there is no net force on the person.  Hence, the person feels no force acting on him.",
        "answer": "straight",
        "options": [
          "straight",
          "curved",
          "banked"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 25,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "However, when the car moves around a curve, the person feels an outward force exerted on him.This is the centrifugal force caused by the effect of inertia.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 83,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "However, when the car moves around a curve, the person feels an outward force exerted on him.This is the centrifugal force caused by the effect of inertia.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 84,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "However, when the car moves around a curve, the person feels an outward force exerted on him.This is the centrifugal force caused by the effect of ______.",
        "answer": "inertia",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 85,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "However, when the car moves around a curve, the person feels an outward force exerted on him.This is the centrifugal force caused by the effect of ______.",
        "answer": "inertia",
        "options": [
          "inertia",
          "gravity",
          "friction"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 26,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "Actually, the centrifugal force is not a real force.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 86,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Actually, the centrifugal force is  a real force, but none talk about this.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 87,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Actually, the ______ force is not a real force.",
        "answer": "centrifugal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 88,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Actually, the ______ force is not a real force.",
        "answer": "centrifugal",
        "options": [
          "centrifugal",
          "centripetal",
          "gravitational"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 27,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The centrifugal force is an apparent or fictitious force which is equal and opposite to the centripetal force.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 89,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The centrifugal force is an apparent or fictitious force which is equal and opposite to the centripetal force.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 90,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The ______ force is an apparent or fictitious force which is equal and opposite to the centripetal force.",
        "answer": "centrifugal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 91,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The ______ force is an apparent or fictitious force which is equal and opposite to the centripetal force.",
        "answer": "centrifugal",
        "options": [
          "centrifugal",
          "centripetal",
          "reaction"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 92,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The centrifugal force is an apparent or fictitious force which is equal and opposite to the ______ force.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 93,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The centrifugal force is an apparent or fictitious force which is equal and opposite to the ______ force.",
        "answer": "centripetal",
        "options": [
          "centripetal",
          "applied",
          "resultant"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 28,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "In a laboratory centrifuge that uses sample test tubes, the radial acceleration causes denser particles to settle to the bottom of the tube, while low density substances rise to the top.This effect is known as sedimentation principle.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 94,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In a laboratory centrifuge that uses sample test tubes, the radial acceleration causes lighter particles to settle to the bottom of the tube, while low density substances rise to the top.This effect is known as sedimentation principle.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 95,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In a laboratory ______ that uses sample test tubes, the radial acceleration causes denser particles to settle to the bottom of the tube, while low density substances rise to the top.This effect is known as sedimentation principle.",
        "answer": "centrifuge",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 96,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In a laboratory ______ that uses sample test tubes, the radial acceleration causes denser particles to settle to the bottom of the tube, while low density substances rise to the top.This effect is known as sedimentation principle.",
        "answer": "centrifuge",
        "options": [
          "centrifuge",
          "microscope",
          "incubator"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 97,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In a laboratory centrifuge that uses sample test tubes, the radial acceleration causes denser particles to settle to the bottom of the tube, while low density substances rise to the top.This effect is known as ______ principle.",
        "answer": "sedimentation",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 98,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In a laboratory centrifuge that uses sample test tubes, the radial acceleration causes denser particles to settle to the bottom of the tube, while low density substances rise to the top.This effect is known as ______ principle.",
        "answer": "sedimentation",
        "options": [
          "sedimentation",
          "flotation",
          "Archimedes'"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 29,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "Centrifugal pump is a hydraulic machine which converts mechanical energy into hydraulic energy.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 99,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Centrifugal pump is a hydraulic machine which converts mechanical energy into hydraulic energy.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 100,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Centrifugal pump is a hydraulic machine which converts mechanical energy into ______ energy.",
        "answer": "hydraulic",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 101,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Centrifugal pump is a hydraulic machine which converts mechanical energy into ______ energy.",
        "answer": "hydraulic",
        "options": [
          "hydraulic",
          "electrical",
          "kinetic"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 30,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The centrifugal action of a washing machine is used in spin drying the clothes.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 102,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The centrifugal action of a washing machine is used in spin drying the clothes.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 103,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The ______ action of a washing machine is used in spin drying the clothes.",
        "answer": "centrifugal",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 104,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The ______ action of a washing machine is used in spin drying the clothes.",
        "answer": "centrifugal",
        "options": [
          "centrifugal",
          "rinsing",
          "heating"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 31,
    "chapter": "Chapter 2",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The centrifugal governor is a device used to measure and regulate the speed of a machine, such as an engine.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 105,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The centrifugal governor is a device used to measure and regulate the speed of a machine, such as an engine.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 106,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The centrifugal governor is a device used to measure and regulate the ______ of a machine, such as an engine.",
        "answer": "speed",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 107,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The centrifugal governor is a device used to measure and regulate the ______ of a machine, such as an engine.",
        "answer": "speed",
        "options": [
          "speed",
          "temperature",
          "torque"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  }
  ]
  },
  {
  "chapter" : 3,
  "chapterName":  "Fluid Dynamics",
  "chapterPhoto":"@drawable/p3",
  "content":[
  {
    "sentenceId": 1,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The study of fluid is two parts: statics and dynamics.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 1,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The study of fluid is two parts: statistics and dynamics.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 2,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The study of fluid is two parts: statics and ______.",
        "answer": "dynamics",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 3,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The study of fluid is two parts: statics and ______.",
        "answer": "dynamics",
        "options": [
          "dynamics", "kinematics", "thermodynamics"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 2,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The study of the flow of liquid is called hydrodynamics.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 4,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The study of the flow of liquid is called hydrodynamics.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 5,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The study of the flow of liquid is called ______.",
        "answer": "hydrodynamics",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 6,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The study of the flow of liquid is called ______.",
        "answer": "hydrodynamics",
        "options": [
          "hydrodynamics", "hydrostatics", "aerodynamics"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 3,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Hydrostatics is the study of liquid at rest.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 7,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Hydrostatics is the study of liquid at rest.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 8,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is the study of liquid at rest.",
        "answer": "Hydrostatics",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 9,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is the study of liquid at rest.",
        "answer": "Hydrostatics",
        "options": [
          "Hydrostatics", "Hydrodynamics", "Fluid mechanics"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 4,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Fluid dynamics is an important application in daily life such as river flow, water distribution systems, and gas pipelines.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 10,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Fluid dynamics is an important application in daily life such as river flow, water distribution systems, and gas pipelines.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 11,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is an important application in daily life such as river flow, water distribution systems, and gas pipelines.",
        "answer": "Fluid dynamics",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 12,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is an important application in daily life such as river flow, water distribution systems, and gas pipelines.",
        "answer": "Fluid dynamics",
        "options": [
          "Fluid dynamics", "Fluid statics", "Aerodynamics"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 5,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Fluid dynamics is used to explain motion through air and underwater.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 13,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Constant dynamics is used to explain motion through air and underwater.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 14,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is used to explain motion through air and underwater.",
        "answer": "Fluid dynamics",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 15,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is used to explain motion through air and underwater.",
        "answer": "Fluid dynamics",
        "options": [
          "Fluid dynamics", "Thermodynamics", "Acoustics"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 6,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Bernoulli’s principle relates pressure, kinetic, and potential energy in streamline flow.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 16,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Bernoulli’s principle relates pressure, kinetic, and potential energy in streamline flow.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 17,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______’s principle relates pressure, kinetic, and potential energy in streamline flow.",
        "answer": "Bernoulli",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 18,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______’s principle relates pressure, kinetic, and potential energy in streamline flow.",
        "answer": "Bernoulli",
        "options": [
          "Bernoulli", "Newton", "Archimedes"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 7,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Viscosity and Stokes’ law describe resistance in fluid flow.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 19,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Viscosity and Stokes’ law describe resistance in fluid flow.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 20,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Viscosity and Stokes’ law describe ______ in fluid flow.",
        "answer": "resistance",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 21,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Viscosity and Stokes’ law describe ______ in fluid flow.",
        "answer": "resistance",
        "options": [
          "resistance", "conductance", "flow rate"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 8,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Cohesion and adhesion explain surface tension in liquids.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 22,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Cohesion and adhesion explain surface tension in liquids.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 23,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ and adhesion explain surface tension in liquids.",
        "answer": "Cohesion",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 24,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ and adhesion explain surface tension in liquids.",
        "answer": "Cohesion",
        "options": [
          "Cohesion", "Adhesion", "Viscosity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 25,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Cohesion and ______ explain surface tension in liquids.",
        "answer": "adhesion",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 26,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Cohesion and ______ explain surface tension in liquids.",
        "answer": "adhesion",
        "options": [
          "adhesion", "Cohesion", "Surface tension"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 9,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Capillarity is the tendency of a liquid to rise or fall in a narrow tube.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 27,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Gravity is the tendency of a liquid to rise or fall in a narrow tube.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 28,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is the tendency of a liquid to rise or fall in a narrow tube.",
        "answer": "Capillarity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 29,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is the tendency of a liquid to rise or fall in a narrow tube.",
        "answer": "Capillarity",
        "options": [
          "Capillarity", "Viscosity", "Density"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 10,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The volume of a gas depends on pressure and temperature, obeying Boyle’s law and Charles’ law.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 30,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The volume of a gas depends on pressure and temperature, obeying Boyle’s law and Charles’ law.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 31,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The volume of a gas depends on ______ and temperature, obeying Boyle’s law and Charles’ law.",
        "answer": "pressure",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 32,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The volume of a gas depends on ______ and temperature, obeying Boyle’s law and Charles’ law.",
        "answer": "pressure",
        "options": [
          "pressure", "volume", "density"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 33,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The volume of a gas depends on pressure and ______, obeying Boyle’s law and Charles’ law.",
        "answer": "temperature",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 34,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The volume of a gas depends on pressure and ______, obeying Boyle’s law and Charles’ law.",
        "answer": "temperature",
        "options": [
          "temperature", "pressure", "viscosity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 11,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "The volume of a liquid is nearly constant if temperature is constant.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 35,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The volume of a liquid is nearly constant if temperature is constant.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 36,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The volume of a liquid is nearly constant if ______ is constant.",
        "answer": "temperature",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 37,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The volume of a liquid is nearly constant if ______ is constant.",
        "answer": "temperature",
        "options": [
          "temperature", "pressure", "volume"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 12,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "A liquid is considered incompressible under constant temperature.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 38,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "A liquid is considered compressible under constant temperature.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 39,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "A liquid is considered ______ under constant temperature.",
        "answer": "incompressible",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 40,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "A liquid is considered ______ under constant temperature.",
        "answer": "incompressible",
        "options": [
          "incompressible", "compressible", "viscous"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 41,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "A liquid is considered incompressible under constant ______.",
        "answer": "temperature",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 42,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "A liquid is considered incompressible under constant ______.",
        "answer": "temperature",
        "options": [
          "temperature", "pressure", "density"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 13,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "In fluid flow, the path of particles is called a streamline.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 43,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In fluid flow, the path of particles is called a streamline.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 44,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In fluid flow, the path of particles is called a ______.",
        "answer": "streamline",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 45,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In fluid flow, the path of particles is called a ______.",
        "answer": "streamline",
        "options": [
          "streamline", "flow path", "trajectory"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 14,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "Motion of fluids can be classified as laminar or turbulent flow.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 46,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Motion of fluids can be classified as laminar or turbulent flow.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 47,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Motion of fluids can be classified as ______ or turbulent flow.",
        "answer": "laminar",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 48,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Motion of fluids can be classified as ______ or turbulent flow.",
        "answer": "laminar",
        "options": [
          "laminar", "turbulent", "steady"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 49,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Motion of fluids can be classified as laminar or ______ flow.",
        "answer": "turbulent",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 50,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Motion of fluids can be classified as laminar or ______ flow.",
        "answer": "turbulent",
        "options": [
          "turbulent", "laminar", "chaotic"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 15,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "In laminar flow, fluid particles move in smooth paths or layers without mixing.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 51,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In laminar flow, fluid particles move in smooth paths or layers without mixing.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 52,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In ______ flow, fluid particles move in smooth paths or layers without mixing.",
        "answer": "laminar",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 53,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In ______ flow, fluid particles move in smooth paths or layers without mixing.",
        "answer": "laminar",
        "options": [
          "laminar", "turbulent", "viscous"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 16,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "In turbulent flow, fluid particles move irregularly with changing direction and speed.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 54,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In turbulent flow, fluid particles move irregularly with changing direction and speed.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 55,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In ______ flow, fluid particles move irregularly with changing direction and speed.",
        "answer": "turbulent",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 56,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In ______ flow, fluid particles move irregularly with changing direction and speed.",
        "answer": "turbulent",
        "options": [
          "turbulent", "laminar", "streamline"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 17,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 1,
    "sentence": "An ideal laminar fluid flow assumes incompressibility and zero viscosity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 57,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "An ideal laminar fluid flow assumes incompressibility and high viscosity.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 58,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An ideal laminar fluid flow assumes incompressibility and ______.",
        "answer": "zero viscosity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 59,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An ideal laminar fluid flow assumes incompressibility and ______.",
        "answer": "zero viscosity",
        "options": [
          "zero viscosity", "high viscosity", "low density"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 18,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The equation of continuity states that A₁v₁ = A₂v₂ for incompressible, non-viscous fluids.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 60,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The equation of continuity states that A₁v₁ = A₂v₂ for incompressible, non-viscous fluids.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 61,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The equation of ______ states that A₁v₁ = A₂v₂ for incompressible, non-viscous fluids.",
        "answer": "continuity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 62,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The equation of ______ states that A₁v₁ = A₂v₂ for incompressible, non-viscous fluids.",
        "answer": "continuity",
        "options": [
          "continuity", "energy", "momentum"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 19,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "The volume flow rate is constant across pipe sections in steady flow.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 63,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The volume flow rate is constant across pipe sections in steady flow.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 64,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The volume flow rate is constant across pipe sections in ______ flow.",
        "answer": "steady",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 65,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The volume flow rate is constant across pipe sections in ______ flow.",
        "answer": "steady",
        "options": [
          "steady", "unsteady", "turbulent"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 20,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 2,
    "sentence": "In a narrower section of a pipe, fluid speed increases and pressure decreases.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 66,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In a narrower section of a pipe, fluid speed increases and pressure decreases.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 67,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In a narrower section of a pipe, fluid speed ______ and pressure decreases.",
        "answer": "increases",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 68,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In a narrower section of a pipe, fluid speed ______ and pressure decreases.",
        "answer": "increases",
        "options": [
          "increases", "decreases", "remains constant"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 69,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In a narrower section of a pipe, fluid speed increases and pressure ______.",
        "answer": "decreases",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 70,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In a narrower section of a pipe, fluid speed increases and pressure ______.",
        "answer": "decreases",
        "options": [
          "decreases", "increases", "remains constant"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 21,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "Bernoulli's principle relates pressure, speed, and height in a flowing fluid.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 71,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Bernoulli's principle relates pressure, speed, and height in a flowing fluid.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 72,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______'s principle relates pressure, speed, and height in a flowing fluid.",
        "answer": "Bernoulli",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 73,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______'s principle relates pressure, speed, and height in a flowing fluid.",
        "answer": "Bernoulli",
        "options": [
          "Bernoulli", "Pascal", "Torricelli"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 22,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 3,
    "sentence": "According to Bernoulli's theorem, the total energy per unit volume is constant in steady flow.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 74,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "According to Bernoulli's theorem, the total energy per unit volume is constant in increasing flow.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 75,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "According to Bernoulli's theorem, the total energy per unit volume is ______ in steady flow.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 76,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "According to Bernoulli's theorem, the total energy per unit volume is ______ in steady flow.",
        "answer": "constant",
        "options": [
          "constant", "variable", "increasing"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 23,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 4,
    "sentence": "An airplane wing generates lift due to pressure differences created by airflow speed.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 77,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "An airplane wing generates lift due to pressure differences created by airflow speed.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 78,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "An airplane wing generates lift due to ______ differences created by airflow speed.",
        "answer": "pressure",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 79,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An airplane wing generates lift due to ______ differences created by airflow speed.",
        "answer": "pressure",
        "options": [
          "pressure", "velocity", "density"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 24,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 4,
    "sentence": "In an insect sprayer, fast air over the nozzle causes low pressure, drawing liquid upward.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 80,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In an insect sprayer, fast air over the nozzle causes low pressure, drawing liquid upward.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 81,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In an insect sprayer, fast air over the nozzle causes ______ pressure, drawing liquid upward.",
        "answer": "low",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 82,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In an insect sprayer, fast air over the nozzle causes ______ pressure, drawing liquid upward.",
        "answer": "low",
        "options": [
          "low", "high", "atmospheric"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 25,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 4,
    "sentence": "The Magnus effect explains the curved path of a spinning ball due to pressure differences.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 83,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The Magnus effect explains the curved path of a spinning ball due to pressure differences.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 84,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The ______ explains the curved path of a spinning ball due to pressure differences.",
        "answer": "Magnus effect",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 85,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The ______ explains the curved path of a spinning ball due to pressure differences.",
        "answer": "Magnus effect",
        "options": [
          "Magnus effect", "Venturi effect", "Bernoulli's principle"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 26,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 4,
    "sentence": "During cyclones, increased air speed over a roof creates lower pressure, causing lift on the roof.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 86,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "During cyclones, increased air speed over a roof creates high pressure, causing lift on the roof.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 87,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "During cyclones, increased air speed over a roof creates ______ pressure, causing lift on the roof.",
        "answer": "lower",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 88,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "During cyclones, increased air speed over a roof creates ______ pressure, causing lift on the roof.",
        "answer": "lower",
        "options": [
          "lower", "higher", "equal"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 27,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Viscosity is the internal resistance of fluid to flow, caused by intermolecular forces.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 89,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Viscosity is the internal resistance of fluid to flow, caused by intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 90,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is the internal resistance of fluid to flow, caused by intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": "Viscosity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 91,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is the internal resistance of fluid to flow, caused by intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": "Viscosity",
        "options": [
          "Viscosity", "Density", "Pressure"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 28,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "A fluid with high viscosity resists flow more than one with low viscosity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 92,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "A fluid with high viscosity resists flow more than one with low viscosity.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 93,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "A fluid with high viscosity resists flow more than one with ______.",
        "answer": "low viscosity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 94,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "A fluid with high viscosity resists flow more than one with ______.",
        "answer": "low viscosity",
        "options": [
          "low viscosity", "high density", "zero viscosity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 29,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Viscosity in liquids decreases with increasing temperature due to reduced intermolecular forces.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 95,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Viscosity in liquids decreases with increasing temperature due to reduced intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 96,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Viscosity in liquids ______ with increasing temperature due to reduced intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": "decreases",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 97,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Viscosity in liquids ______ with increasing temperature due to reduced intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": "decreases",
        "options": [
          "decreases", "increases", "remains constant"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 30,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Viscosity in gases increases with increasing temperature due to increased molecular collisions.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 98,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Viscosity in gases decrease with increasing temperature due to increased molecular collisions.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 99,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Viscosity in gases ______ with increasing temperature due to increased molecular collisions.",
        "answer": "increases",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 100,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Viscosity in gases ______ with increasing temperature due to increased molecular collisions.",
        "answer": "increases",
        "options": [
          "increases", "decreases", "remains constant"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 31,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Viscosity is an intensive property and does not depend on the amount of substance.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 101,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Viscosity is an intensive property and does not depend on the amount of substance.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 102,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Viscosity is an ______ property and does not depend on the amount of substance.",
        "answer": "intensive",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 103,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Viscosity is an ______ property and does not depend on the amount of substance.",
        "answer": "intensive",
        "options": [
          "intensive", "extensive", "derived"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 32,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "The SI unit of viscosity is the pascal second (Pa·s).",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 104,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The SI unit of surface tension is the pascal second (Pa·s).",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 105,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The SI unit of viscosity is the ______ (Pa·s).",
        "answer": "pascal second",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 106,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The SI unit of viscosity is the ______ (Pa·s).",
        "answer": "pascal second",
        "options": [
          "pascal second", "poise", "newton per meter"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 33,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "The method of measuring a fluid’s resistance to flow under applied force is called dynamic viscosity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 107,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The method of measuring a fluid’s resistance to flow under applied force is called kinematic viscosity.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 108,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The method of measuring a fluid’s resistance to flow under applied force is called ______.",
        "answer": "dynamic viscosity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 109,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The method of measuring a fluid’s resistance to flow under applied force is called ______.",
        "answer": "dynamic viscosity",
        "options": [
          "dynamic viscosity", "kinematic viscosity", "fluid friction"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 34,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "The resistive flow of a fluid under the weight of gravity is measured as kinematic viscosity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 110,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The resistive flow of a fluid under the weight of gravity is measured as kinematic viscosity.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 111,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The resistive flow of a fluid under the weight of gravity is measured as ______.",
        "answer": "kinematic viscosity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 112,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The resistive flow of a fluid under the weight of gravity is measured as ______.",
        "answer": "kinematic viscosity",
        "options": [
          "kinematic viscosity", "dynamic viscosity", "fluid density"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 35,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Kinematic viscosity is more useful than dynamic viscosity (absolute viscosity).",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 113,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Kinematic viscosity is more useful than dynamic viscosity (absolute viscosity).",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 114,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Kinematic viscosity is more useful than ______ (absolute viscosity).",
        "answer": "dynamic viscosity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 115,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Kinematic viscosity is more useful than ______ (absolute viscosity).",
        "answer": "dynamic viscosity",
        "options": [
          "dynamic viscosity", "kinematic viscosity", "absolute pressure"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 36,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Newton’s law of viscosity states that the shear stress between adjacent layers of fluid is directly proportional to the negative value of the velocity gradient between the same two adjacent fluid layers.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 116,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Newton’s law of viscosity states that the shear stress between adjacent layers of fluid is directly proportional to the negative value of the velocity gradient between the same two adjacent fluid layers.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 117,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Newton’s law of viscosity states that the ______ between adjacent layers of fluid is directly proportional to the negative value of the velocity gradient between the same two adjacent fluid layers.",
        "answer": "shear stress",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 118,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Newton’s law of viscosity states that the ______ between adjacent layers of fluid is directly proportional to the negative value of the velocity gradient between the same two adjacent fluid layers.",
        "answer": "shear stress",
        "options": [
          "shear stress", "normal stress", "pressure"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 37,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Shear stress in fluids is defined by the equation 𝝉 = −𝜼 (𝒅𝒗/𝒅𝒚), where 𝜼 is the coefficient of viscosity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 119,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Shear stress in fluids is defined by the equation 𝝉 = −𝜼 (𝒅𝒗/𝒅𝒚), where 𝜼 is the coefficient of viscosity.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 120,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Shear stress in fluids is defined by the equation 𝝉 = −𝜼 (𝒅𝒗/𝒅𝒚), where 𝜼 is the ______.",
        "answer": "coefficient of viscosity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 121,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Shear stress in fluids is defined by the equation 𝝉 = −𝜼 (𝒅𝒗/𝒅𝒚), where 𝜼 is the ______.",
        "answer": "coefficient of viscosity",
        "options": [
          "coefficient of viscosity", "density", "specific gravity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 38,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "In Newton's law of viscosity, shear stress is the force per unit area between adjacent layers of fluid.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 122,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In Newton's law of viscosity, shear stress is the force per unit area between adjacent layers of fluid.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 123,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In Newton's law of viscosity, ______ is the force per unit area between adjacent layers of fluid.",
        "answer": "shear stress",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 124,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In Newton's law of viscosity, ______ is the force per unit area between adjacent layers of fluid.",
        "answer": "shear stress",
        "options": [
          "shear stress", "tensile stress", "bulk modulus"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 39,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Kinematic viscosity is the ratio of shear stress to the velocity gradient in a fluid.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 125,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Kinematic velocity is the ratio of shear stress to the velocity gradient in a fluid.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 126,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is the ratio of shear stress to the velocity gradient in a fluid.",
        "answer": "Kinematic viscosity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 127,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is the ratio of shear stress to the velocity gradient in a fluid.",
        "answer": "Kinematic viscosity",
        "options": [
          "Kinematic viscosity", "Dynamic viscosity", "Fluid density"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 40,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Stokes' law, derived by George G. Stokes in 1851, expresses the drag force resisting the fall of small spherical objects through a fluid under gravity.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 128,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Stokes' law, derived by George G. Stokes in 1851, expresses the drag force resisting the fall of small spherical objects through a fluid under buoyancy.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 129,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Stokes' law, derived by George G. Stokes in 1851, expresses the drag force resisting the fall of small spherical objects through a fluid under ______.",
        "answer": "gravity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 130,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Stokes' law, derived by George G. Stokes in 1851, expresses the drag force resisting the fall of small spherical objects through a fluid under ______.",
        "answer": "gravity",
        "options": [
          "gravity", "buoyancy", "friction"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 41,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "Stokes’ law is used to determine kinematic viscosity by measuring the velocity of a small sphere falling through a fluid.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 131,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Stokes’ law is used to determine kinematic viscosity by measuring the velocity of a small sphere falling through a fluid.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 132,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Stokes’ law is used to determine ______ viscosity by measuring the velocity of a small sphere falling through a fluid.",
        "answer": "kinematic",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 133,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Stokes’ law is used to determine ______ viscosity by measuring the velocity of a small sphere falling through a fluid.",
        "answer": "kinematic",
        "options": [
          "kinematic", "dynamic", "absolute"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 42,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "At terminal velocity, the upward and downward forces on a falling sphere are in balance, where drag force and upward thrust equal the weight of the sphere.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 134,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "At terminal velocity, the upward and downward forces on a falling sphere are in balance, where drag force and upward thrust equal the weight of the sphere.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 135,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "At terminal velocity, the upward and downward forces on a falling sphere are in balance, where ______ and upward thrust equal the weight of the sphere.",
        "answer": "drag force",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 136,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "At terminal velocity, the upward and downward forces on a falling sphere are in balance, where ______ and upward thrust equal the weight of the sphere.",
        "answer": "drag force",
        "options": [
          "drag force", "gravity", "buoyant force"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 137,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "At terminal velocity, the upward and downward forces on a falling sphere are in balance, where drag force and ______ equal the weight of the sphere.",
        "answer": "upward thrust",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 138,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "At terminal velocity, the upward and downward forces on a falling sphere are in balance, where drag force and ______ equal the weight of the sphere.",
        "answer": "upward thrust",
        "options": [
          "upward thrust", "downward pull", "net force"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 43,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "The forces acting on a sphere falling through a fluid include weight, drag force, and upward thrust.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 139,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The forces acting on a sphere falling through a fluid include weight, drag force, and upward thrust.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 140,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The forces acting on a sphere falling through a fluid include ______, drag force, and upward thrust.",
        "answer": "weight",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 141,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The forces acting on a sphere falling through a fluid include ______, drag force, and upward thrust.",
        "answer": "weight",
        "options": [
          "weight", "mass", "buoyancy"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 142,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The forces acting on a sphere falling through a fluid include weight, ______, and upward thrust.",
        "answer": "drag force",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 143,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The forces acting on a sphere falling through a fluid include weight, ______, and upward thrust.",
        "answer": "drag force",
        "options": [
          "drag force", "lift force", "thrust"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 144,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The forces acting on a sphere falling through a fluid include weight, drag force, and ______.",
        "answer": "upward thrust",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 145,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The forces acting on a sphere falling through a fluid include weight, drag force, and ______.",
        "answer": "upward thrust",
        "options": [
          "upward thrust", "tension", "friction"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 44,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "The formula for drag force in Stokes' law is F = 6π𝜼rv, where r is the radius of the sphere and v is the velocity of the sphere.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 146,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The formula for drag force in Stokes' law is F = 6π𝜼v, where  v is the velocity of the sphere.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 147,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The formula for ______ in Stokes' law is F = 6π𝜼rv, where r is the radius of the sphere and v is the velocity of the sphere.",
        "answer": "drag force",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 148,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The formula for ______ in Stokes' law is F = 6π𝜼rv, where r is the radius of the sphere and v is the velocity of the sphere.",
        "answer": "drag force",
        "options": [
          "drag force", "lift force", "gravitational force"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 45,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 5,
    "sentence": "In Stokes' law, the terminal velocity is the constant velocity at which a spherical object falls through a fluid.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 149,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In Stokes' law, the terminal velocity is the constant velocity at which a spherical object falls through a fluid.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 150,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In Stokes' law, the ______ is the constant velocity at which a spherical object falls through a fluid.",
        "answer": "terminal velocity",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 151,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In Stokes' law, the ______ is the constant velocity at which a spherical object falls through a fluid.",
        "answer": "terminal velocity",
        "options": [
          "terminal velocity", "initial velocity", "average velocity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 46,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Surface tension is the tendency of the surface of a liquid to behave like a stretched elastic membrane due to the cohesive forces between liquid molecules.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 152,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Surface tension is the tendency of the surface of a liquid to behave like a stretched elastic membrane due to the cohesive forces between liquid molecules.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 153,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is the tendency of the surface of a liquid to behave like a stretched elastic membrane due to the cohesive forces between liquid molecules.",
        "answer": "Surface tension",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 154,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is the tendency of the surface of a liquid to behave like a stretched elastic membrane due to the cohesive forces between liquid molecules.",
        "answer": "Surface tension",
        "options": [
          "Surface tension", "Viscosity", "Adhesion"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 47,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Cohesion refers to the forces between molecules of the same substance, such as in surface tension.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 155,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Cohesion refers to the forces between molecules of the same substance, such as in surface tension.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 156,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Cohesion refers to the forces between ______ of the same substance, such as in surface tension.",
        "answer": "molecules",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 157,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Cohesion refers to the forces between ______ of the same substance, such as in surface tension.",
        "answer": "molecules",
        "options": [
          "molecules", "atoms", "compounds"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 158,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Cohesion refers to the forces between molecules of the same substance, such as in ______.",
        "answer": "surface tension",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 159,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Cohesion refers to the forces between molecules of the same substance, such as in ______.",
        "answer": "surface tension",
        "options": [
          "surface tension", "capillarity", "viscosity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 48,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Cohesion makes water molecules pull together, making the water surface stretch like an elastic skin.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 160,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Cohesion makes water molecules pull together, making the water surface stretch like an elastic skin.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 161,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ makes water molecules pull together, making the water surface stretch like an elastic skin.",
        "answer": "Cohesion",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 162,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ makes water molecules pull together, making the water surface stretch like an elastic skin.",
        "answer": "Cohesion",
        "options": [
          "Cohesion", "Adhesion", "Gravity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 49,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Surface tension is the reason a water strider can stride along the water surface without sinking.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 163,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Density is the key reason a water strider can stride along the water surface without sinking.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 164,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is the reason a water strider can stride along the water surface without sinking.",
        "answer": "Surface tension",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 165,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is the reason a water strider can stride along the water surface without sinking.",
        "answer": "Surface tension",
        "options": [
          "Surface tension", "Buoyancy", "Low density"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 50,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Surface tension is defined as the force per unit length that acts across any line on a surface, tending to pull the surface apart.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 166,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Surface tension is defined as the force per unit length that acts across any line on a surface, tending to pull the surface apart.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 167,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is defined as the force per unit length that acts across any line on a surface, tending to pull the surface apart.",
        "answer": "Surface tension",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 168,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is defined as the force per unit length that acts across any line on a surface, tending to pull the surface apart.",
        "answer": "Surface tension",
        "options": [
          "Surface tension", "Pressure", "Force"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 51,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "The SI unit of surface tension is newton per metre (N m⁻¹).",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 169,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The SI unit of surface tension is newton per metre (N m⁻¹).",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 170,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The SI unit of ______ is newton per metre (N m⁻¹).",
        "answer": "surface tension",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 171,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The SI unit of ______ is newton per metre (N m⁻¹).",
        "answer": "surface tension",
        "options": [
          "surface tension", "viscosity", "pressure"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 52,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Capillary action is defined as the spontaneous flow of a liquid into a narrow tube or porous material.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 172,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Capillary action is defined as the spontaneous flow of a liquid into a narrow tube or porous material.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 173,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is defined as the spontaneous flow of a liquid into a narrow tube or porous material.",
        "answer": "Capillary action",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 174,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is defined as the spontaneous flow of a liquid into a narrow tube or porous material.",
        "answer": "Capillary action",
        "options": [
          "Capillary action", "Surface tension", "Osmosis"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 53,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Capillary action is caused by the combination of cohesive forces of the liquid and the adhesive forces between the liquid and the tube material.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 175,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Capillary action is caused by the combination of cohesive forces of the liquid and the adhesive forces between the liquid and the tube material.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 54,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Cohesion refers to forces between molecules of the same substance, while adhesion refers to forces between molecules of different substances.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 176,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Cohesion refers to forces between molecules of the same substance, while adhesion refers to forces between molecules of different substances.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 177,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ refers to forces between molecules of the same substance, while adhesion refers to forces between molecules of different substances.",
        "answer": "Cohesion",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 178,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ refers to forces between molecules of the same substance, while adhesion refers to forces between molecules of different substances.",
        "answer": "Cohesion",
        "options": [
          "Cohesion", "Adhesion", "Affinity"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 179,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Cohesion refers to forces between molecules of the same substance, while ______ refers to forces between molecules of different substances.",
        "answer": "adhesion",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 180,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Cohesion refers to forces between molecules of the same substance, while ______ refers to forces between molecules of different substances.",
        "answer": "adhesion",
        "options": [
          "adhesion", "Cohesion", "Attraction"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 55,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "In capillary action, cohesive and adhesive forces pull the liquid into the tube.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 181,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In capillary action, cohesive and adhesive forces only pull up the liquid into the tube.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 182,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In capillary action, ______ and adhesive forces pull the liquid into the tube.",
        "answer": "cohesive",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 183,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In capillary action, ______ and adhesive forces pull the liquid into the tube.",
        "answer": "cohesive",
        "options": [
          "cohesive", "adhesive", "gravitational"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 56,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "In order for wicking to occur, a tube needs to be sufficiently small in diameter.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 184,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "In order for wicking to occur, a tube needs to be sufficiently small in diameter.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 185,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "In order for wicking to occur, a tube needs to be sufficiently ______ in diameter.",
        "answer": "small",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 186,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "In order for wicking to occur, a tube needs to be sufficiently ______ in diameter.",
        "answer": "small",
        "options": [
          "small", "large", "wide"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 57,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Capillary action is also the rise or depression of a liquid in a narrow tube of small cross-sectional area, such as the spaces between fibers in a towel or openings in a porous material.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 187,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Capillary action is also the rise or depression of a liquid in a narrow tube of small cross-sectional area, such as the spaces between fibers in a towel or openings in a porous material.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 188,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ is also the rise or depression of a liquid in a narrow tube of small cross-sectional area, such as the spaces between fibers in a towel or openings in a porous material.",
        "answer": "Capillary action",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 189,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ is also the rise or depression of a liquid in a narrow tube of small cross-sectional area, such as the spaces between fibers in a towel or openings in a porous material.",
        "answer": "Capillary action",
        "options": [
          "Capillary action", "Diffusion", "Convection"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 58,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "The rise of water underneath the ground is an example of capillary action.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 190,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The rise of water underneath the ground is an example of gravity action.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 191,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The rise of water underneath the ground is an example of ______.",
        "answer": "capillary action",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 192,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The rise of water underneath the ground is an example of ______.",
        "answer": "capillary action",
        "options": [
          "capillary action", "gravity feed", "siphoning"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 59,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Capillary action helps bring water up into the roots of plants.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 193,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Capillary action helps bring water up into the roots of plants.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 194,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "______ helps bring water up into the roots of plants.",
        "answer": "Capillary action",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 195,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "______ helps bring water up into the roots of plants.",
        "answer": "Capillary action",
        "options": [
          "Capillary action", "Photosynthesis", "Transpiration pull"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 60,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "When a glass tube with a small inside diameter is dipped into water, the water rises into the tube due to capillary action.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 196,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When a glass tube with a small inside diameter is dipped into water, the water rises into the tube due to capillary action.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 197,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When a glass tube with a small inside diameter is dipped into water, the water rises into the tube due to ______.",
        "answer": "capillary action",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 198,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When a glass tube with a small inside diameter is dipped into water, the water rises into the tube due to ______.",
        "answer": "capillary action",
        "options": [
          "capillary action", "pressure difference", "buoyancy"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 61,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "The smaller the bore, the higher the water will rise due to capillary action.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 199,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "The smaller the bore, the shorter the water will rise due to capillary action.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 200,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "The ______ the bore, the higher the water will rise due to capillary action.",
        "answer": "smaller",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 201,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The ______ the bore, the higher the water will rise due to capillary action.",
        "answer": "smaller",
        "options": [
          "smaller", "larger", "wider"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 62,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Liquids that rise in small bore tubes inserted into the liquid are said to wet the tube, whereas liquids that are depressed within thin tubes below the surface of the surrounding liquid do not wet the tube.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 202,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Liquids that rise in small bore tubes inserted into the liquid are said to wet the tube, whereas liquids that are depressed within thin tubes below the surface of the surrounding liquid do not wet the tube.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 203,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Liquids that rise in small bore tubes inserted into the liquid are said to ______ the tube, whereas liquids that are depressed within thin tubes below the surface of the surrounding liquid do not wet the tube.",
        "answer": "wet",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 204,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Liquids that rise in small bore tubes inserted into the liquid are said to ______ the tube, whereas liquids that are depressed within thin tubes below the surface of the surrounding liquid do not wet the tube.",
        "answer": "wet",
        "options": [
          "wet", "absorb", "repel"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 63,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Capillarity does not occur for non-wetting liquids.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 205,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Capillarity does not occur for non-wetting liquids.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 206,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Capillarity does not occur for ______ liquids.",
        "answer": "non-wetting",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 207,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Capillarity does not occur for ______ liquids.",
        "answer": "non-wetting",
        "options": [
          "non-wetting", "wetting", "viscous"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 64,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "When a glass tube is dipped into water, the adhesion between glass and water causes a thin film of water to be drawn up over the inner and outer surfaces of the tube.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 208,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "When a glass tube is dipped into water, the adhesion between glass and water causes a thin film of water to be drawn up over the inner and outer surfaces of the tube.",
        "answer": true,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 209,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "When a glass tube is dipped into water, the ______ between glass and water causes a thin film of water to be drawn up over the inner and outer surfaces of the tube.",
        "answer": "adhesion",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 210,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When a glass tube is dipped into water, the ______ between glass and water causes a thin film of water to be drawn up over the inner and outer surfaces of the tube.",
        "answer": "adhesion",
        "options": [
          "adhesion", "cohesion", "surface tension"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentenceId": 65,
    "chapter": "Chapter 3",
    "section": 6,
    "sentence": "Since the adhesive force is greater than the cohesive force, the water level rises until there is a sufficient mass of liquid for gravitational forces to overcome these intermolecular forces.",
    "questions": [
      {
        "questionId": 211,
        "question_type": "tf",
        "question": "Since the adhesive force is smaller than the cohesive force, the water level rises until there is a sufficient mass of liquid for gravitational forces to overcome these intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": false,
        "options": [
          true,
          false
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 212,
        "question_type": "fb",
        "question": "Since the adhesive force is ______ than the cohesive force, the water level rises until there is a sufficient mass of liquid for gravitational forces to overcome these intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": "greater",
        "options": null,
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      },
      {
        "questionId": 213,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Since the adhesive force is ______ than the cohesive force, the water level rises until there is a sufficient mass of liquid for gravitational forces to overcome these intermolecular forces.",
        "answer": "greater",
        "options": [
          "greater", "smaller", "equal"
        ],
        "practiceCount": 0,
        "important": false,
        "mistake": false
      }
    ]
  }
]
  }
]